What do you do when the sign test and the hypothesis test don't agree?
如果符号检验的结果与假设检验不一致该怎么办？
Or what if you have significant results on weekends but not on weekdays?
或者 周末的数据具有显著性但工作日相反时该怎么办？
>> Well, the first thing you want to do as we talked about is take a really
你要做的第一件事我们已经讨论过了
critical look about how your feature functions.
就是仔细观察实验特征是如何发挥作用的
Is it really operating differently for different subgroups for
它的运行过程是否
example on a particular platform.
因不同的平台而异 比如只适合一种平台？
But there are real statistical reasons that you
但是某些统计因素确实
might get counter-intuitive results.
会导致与正常直觉相反的结果
One of them that shows off common lane experiments is called Simpson's paradox.
其中常见于一般实验中的是“辛普森悖论”
What it means is that there's a bunch of different subgroups in your data
它指的是 数据可分成许多不同的小组
like user populations.
如用户数量
And within each subgroup, the results are stable but when you aggregate them
而且每个小组的结果单独看来都是稳定的
all together, it's the mix of subgroups that actually drives your result.
但是一旦合并考虑 各小组的数据共同对最终结果产生影响
>> That doesn't even sound possible.
听起来好像不太可能
Can you give me an example?
你能举例说明吗？
>> So the example that most people like was actually a real example about
大部分人喜欢的例子是
graduate admissions at Berkeley.
伯克利大学研究生招生的实例
So what was happening is that in aggregate,
将各小组的数据合并后
if you looked at the number of people who are accepted divided by the number
观察录取率 即录取人数除以申请人数
that applied, the rate of women being accepted was statistically significantly
发现 女生录取率比男生录取率低的值具有统计显著性
lower than men being accepted, which seemed bad.
这看起来不太舒服
But when you looked at it by department, there were actually departments where
但是再观察各院系的录取率后
women were accepted at a higher rate than men.
发现某些院系的女生录取率高于男生
So how can that be?
这是怎么回事呢？
The answer turned out to be that you had to look at it by department, because
原来是因为 各院系的录取率是变量 从 6% 至 60% 不等
the acceptance rates by department were variable, from 6% to as much as 60%.
所以应当按照院系分别分析录取率
And what was happening is that more women were applying to the smaller
事实是
departments that had a very low acceptance rate.
更多女生申请了录取率很低的小院系
So when you aggregated the numbers,
所以不考虑院系差异 将数据合并后
ignoring department, you saw women accepted at a lower rate.
就会发现 女生的录取率很低
But if you looked at each department individually,
但是分别计算各院系的录取情况后
the rates were very comparable between men and women.
则发现 男生和女生的录取率具有可比性
>> Okay, and how does this apply to our experiment?
这种情况如何发生在我们的实验中？
>> Well, you can get this happening on our experiment because you have these
我们的实验会发生这样情况
subgroups like people who use it more on weekdays or
是因为实验涉及两组数据
people use it more on weekends.
即工作日和周末更多访问页面的用户人数
And you may find that, for example,
比如说 你会发现
new users are correlated with weekend use and you know,
新用户的使用情况与周末使用相关
experienced users who react differently are correlated with weekday use.
而资深用户则相反 其使用情况与工作日相关
And so what sometimes you find in these cases is that what drives the results of
所以有时你会从中发现 对实验结果产生影响的是
your experiment are how many people from each group you get.
各组的人数
Within each group, their behavior is stable,
在各小组范围内 用户的行为具有稳定性
you can get a statistically significant result or an insignificant result.
得出的分析结果可能具有统计显著性 也可能没有
But when you add them all together,
但是如果把各小组的数据合并起来
all the changes in your traffic mix are driving the results.
分析结果会受到所有小组流量变化的影响
In a minute, Caroline's going to take you through an example of how that
等一会儿 Caroline 会通过实例为你讲解
happens when you do an experiment analysis.
实验分析过程中如何产生“辛普森悖论”